<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Standard library on JIPipe for ImageJ</title>
    <link>https://applied-systems-biology.github.io/jipipe/documentation/standard-library/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Standard library on JIPipe for ImageJ</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://applied-systems-biology.github.io/jipipe/documentation/standard-library/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ImageJ integration</title>
      <link>https://applied-systems-biology.github.io/jipipe/documentation/standard-library/imagej-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://applied-systems-biology.github.io/jipipe/documentation/standard-library/imagej-integration/</guid>
      <description>The ImageJ integration library integrates common data types from ImageJ into JIPipe:
 Multi-dimensional images (ImagePlus). The standard output file format are TIFF files. Result tables. They are serialized to CSV files. Region of interest (ROI Manager). JIPipe handles ROI as *.zip files.  The ImageJ data types are marked as accessible from outside JIPipe, meaning that algorithms that only use those types can be executed standalone
Image data types Various ImageJ algorithms only work on data with a specific color type, or dimensionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-parameter algorithms</title>
      <link>https://applied-systems-biology.github.io/jipipe/documentation/standard-library/multi-parameter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://applied-systems-biology.github.io/jipipe/documentation/standard-library/multi-parameter/</guid>
      <description>Most algorithms allow handling of multiple parameters via an additional slot that can be optionally enabled. You can find the setting in an algorithm&amp;rsquo;s settings as Multiple parameters. On selecting the item, a new slot will appear that consumes parameter data.
To define parameters, use the algorithms found in Add data &amp;gt; Parameters. There are currently two data source algorithms available:
 Define parameter defines a single set of parameters Define multiple parameters lets you define a table of parameters  Use Process &amp;gt; Merge &amp;gt; Merge slots to merge multiple parameter sets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filesystem algorithms</title>
      <link>https://applied-systems-biology.github.io/jipipe/documentation/standard-library/filesystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://applied-systems-biology.github.io/jipipe/documentation/standard-library/filesystem/</guid>
      <description>The JIPipe standard library contains data types and algorithms to apply file system operations. The common use case is to extract the list of input files for the following algorithms.
The filesystem library has two basic data types:
 A  File contains a path to a file A  Folder contains a path to a folder A Path contains a path to a file or folder  In the Add data menu you can define one file/folder or a list of files/folders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data annotation algorithms</title>
      <link>https://applied-systems-biology.github.io/jipipe/documentation/standard-library/annotations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://applied-systems-biology.github.io/jipipe/documentation/standard-library/annotations/</guid>
      <description>Data annotations allow JIPipe algorithms and users to assign an unique data set to the data located in a data slot. The standard library contains various algorithms that allow to generate, manipulate, and utilize those annotations.
We recommend to use the algorithms in Annotation &amp;gt; Generate while setting up filesystem operations or any other import step to prevent issues in following algorithm steps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plots and tables</title>
      <link>https://applied-systems-biology.github.io/jipipe/documentation/standard-library/plots-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://applied-systems-biology.github.io/jipipe/documentation/standard-library/plots-tables/</guid>
      <description>The standard library contains algorithms and data types that allows to manipulate tables, and create plots. The table data type is the JIPipe wrapper for the ImageJ results table (see ImageJ integration).
Manipulating tables Table manipulation operations are located in Process &amp;gt; Tables and allow you to add, remove, or replace columns.
Creating plots Plots can be created via the Analyze &amp;gt; Plot &amp;gt; Plot tables algorithm that processes each incoming result table and produces an automatically generated plot.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>