<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Installation on JIPipe for ImageJ</title>
    <link>https://www.jipipe.org/installation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Installation on JIPipe for ImageJ</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.jipipe.org/installation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ImageJ Dependencies</title>
      <link>https://www.jipipe.org/installation/dependencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jipipe.org/installation/dependencies/</guid>
      <description>JIPipe has various dependencies in form of ImageJ update sites that are not always provided via the Fiji update site or the ZIP package. During the startup of the software, JIPipe will automatically check for the appropriate ImageJ update sites and will guide you through the installation of all necessary libraries.
The dependency installation was revised in JIPipe version 1.74.0. Please follow the appropriate procedures in the tutorial below.
 JIPipe 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regarding OMERO</title>
      <link>https://www.jipipe.org/installation/omero/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jipipe.org/installation/omero/</guid>
      <description>If you are installing JIPipe via the ImageJ updater site, you might have noticed a directory jars/omero that will be downloaded with the package.
It contains the absolute minimum of files to use OMERO for uploading and downloading images. We cannot guarantee that the JIPipe-provided OMERO libraries are compatible with your server setup or sufficient for any task outside basic image uploading and downloading.
👉 We strongly recommend to install one of the OMERO packages from the ImageJ updater.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JIPipe extensions</title>
      <link>https://www.jipipe.org/installation/extensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jipipe.org/installation/extensions/</guid>
      <description>Table Of Contents  Installing new extensions Activating extensions    Installing new extensions JIPipe extensions are ImageJ plugins and thus can be installed just as any plugin.
Available options are:
 Installation via the Fiji updater Manual installation by copying the files into the plugins or jars directory  Older JIPipe versions (1.73.x or older) will automatically load all extensions during the startup. This behavior was changed in JIPipe 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
