<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Creating a data type on JIPipe for ImageJ</title>
    <link>https://applied-systems-biology.github.io/jipipe/documentation-java-api/data-type/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Creating a data type on JIPipe for ImageJ</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://applied-systems-biology.github.io/jipipe/documentation-java-api/data-type/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Result view</title>
      <link>https://applied-systems-biology.github.io/jipipe/documentation-java-api/data-type/result-ui/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://applied-systems-biology.github.io/jipipe/documentation-java-api/data-type/result-ui/</guid>
      <description>After processing, users should be able to continue processing the data from within JIPipe. The data instances are cleared from memory after processing, meaning that the data needs to be loaded from its output folder after processing.
An user interface is shown when a user select a row in the results table. This UI can be replaced with a custom one that is designed to handle this specific data type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preview from results folder</title>
      <link>https://applied-systems-biology.github.io/jipipe/documentation-java-api/data-type/result-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://applied-systems-biology.github.io/jipipe/documentation-java-api/data-type/result-preview/</guid>
      <description>While JIPipeData allows you to define a function for previewing, this only works for data already present in memory. To allow previewing of data stored in a results folder, you need to suppy a JIPipeResultDataSlotPreviewUI that loads the data from disk and generates a preview. We recommend to use JIPipeAsyncResultDataPlotPreviewUI, which only requires you to supply a method for loading the data from disk. This class will offload the loading and preview generation into a separate thread to prevent the UI from freezing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>